<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>This is Marshal</title>
    <link>https://www.marshalgao.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on This is Marshal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hku.hk&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;The University of Hong Kong&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2020 09:52:19 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.marshalgao.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>产品经理方向选择</title>
      <link>https://www.marshalgao.com/posts/2020/10/%E4%BA%A7%E5%93%81%E7%BB%8F%E7%90%86%E6%96%B9%E5%90%91%E9%80%89%E6%8B%A9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2020 09:52:19 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.marshalgao.com/posts/2020/10/%E4%BA%A7%E5%93%81%E7%BB%8F%E7%90%86%E6%96%B9%E5%90%91%E9%80%89%E6%8B%A9/</guid>
      <description>B端、C端产品从业市场  C端产品经理更多的是要面向用户，即to consumer。个人感觉现如今C端产品经理需求量即将饱和、竞争压力大，而且从长远角度看，B端产品经理的职业发展空间会更广阔。 B端相较于C端，更多的是在某一个领域与互联网结合的产品，比如需要服务企业方向的SaaS。B端产品发展前景广阔，但需要变换产品思维，门槛相较于C端产品经理更高，而且更注重产品对应方向领域相关知识的学习。  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ICOM6045 Cryptography</title>
      <link>https://www.marshalgao.com/posts/2020/10/icom6045-cryptography/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2020 23:12:13 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.marshalgao.com/posts/2020/10/icom6045-cryptography/</guid>
      <description>Overview Security Threats (explain basically)
 Content  eavesdropping: the message would be listened by others when you communicate with your friends, using email or whatsapp masquerading: identity stealing message tampering: someone modify the message in the middle replaying: receive the same message twice, it is dangerous in transactions, but not in instant message, etc  Machine  infiltration: receive marewares (can control PC or smart phones) from hackers  Traffic  traffic analysis: only interestes in how to communicate denial of service: make others cannot access the services   Security Services (implemented by security mechanisms)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>产品经理学习路线</title>
      <link>https://www.marshalgao.com/posts/2020/10/%E4%BA%A7%E5%93%81%E7%BB%8F%E7%90%86%E5%AD%A6%E4%B9%A0%E8%B7%AF%E7%BA%BF/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 11:21:28 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.marshalgao.com/posts/2020/10/%E4%BA%A7%E5%93%81%E7%BB%8F%E7%90%86%E5%AD%A6%E4%B9%A0%E8%B7%AF%E7%BA%BF/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ICOM6012 Transport Layer</title>
      <link>https://www.marshalgao.com/posts/2020/10/icom6012-transport-layer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2020 13:50:12 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.marshalgao.com/posts/2020/10/icom6012-transport-layer/</guid>
      <description>Transport-layer Services Transport Services and Protocols
 Provide logical communication (actually accomplished by network layer) between app processes on different hosts  logical communication means a pair of hosts is not connected physically, but it seems that they are connected by channel   Transport protocols run in end systems  send side: breaks app messages into segments (if needed), passes to network layer  using segment header, including port number, to communicate with the socket of receiver  receive side: reassembles segemnts into messages, uses segement header (or port number) to pass to application layer  More than one transport protocol available to apps  Majority: TCP and UDP  TCP: reliable, in-order delivery  congestion control flow control connection setup  UDP: unreliable, unordered delivery  no-frills extension of &amp;quot;best-effort&amp;quot; IP   Others: SCTP and DCCP  These protocols are very limited, so we just ignore them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://www.marshalgao.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 23:27:48 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.marshalgao.com/about/</guid>
      <description>This is Marshal. Currently, I am studying for a master&#39;s degree at the University of Hong Kong. My idea for blogging came from the Team Rocket, including Pseudoyu and Misty. In the blog, I would record my relevant courses of Electronic Commerce and Internet Computing of HKU, my interesting codes of LeetCode, knowledge and perspective of product manager, my personal thoughts and ideas about the life and friendship and vlogs about personal life in Hong Kong.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New</title>
      <link>https://www.marshalgao.com/posts/2020/10/new/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 19:52:36 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.marshalgao.com/posts/2020/10/new/</guid>
      <description>Bitcoin and Cryptocurrency Technologies Lecture 1 Introduction to Crypto and Cryptocurrencies Hash Function
 Takes any string as input Fixed-size output Efficiently computable  Security Properties
 Collision-free  Nobody can find x and y such as &amp;ldquo;x!=y and H(x)=H(y)&amp;quot;   Hiding  Given H(x), it&amp;rsquo;s infeasible to find x   Puzzle-friendly  For every possible output value y, if k is chosen from a distribution with high min-entropy, then it&amp;rsquo;s infeasible to find x such as H(k|x)=y    SHA-256 Hash Function</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[1] Two Sum</title>
      <link>https://www.marshalgao.com/posts/2020/10/1-two-sum/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 18:24:14 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.marshalgao.com/posts/2020/10/1-two-sum/</guid>
      <description>Question: Given an array of integers nums and an integer target, return indices of the two numbers such that they add up to target.
You may assume that each input would have exactly one solution, and you may not use the same element twice.
You can return the answer in any order.
Example 1: Input: nums = [2,7,11,15], target = 9 Output: [0,1] Output: Because nums[0] + nums[1] == 9, we return [0, 1].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vlog 2 Quarantine Diary</title>
      <link>https://www.marshalgao.com/posts/2020/09/vlog-2-quarantine-diary/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 14:12:35 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.marshalgao.com/posts/2020/09/vlog-2-quarantine-diary/</guid>
      <description>   疫情期间赴港上学隔离14天的生活即将结束，刚刚上完第一节课，视频传传好，我要冲了，努力学习！ 再次感谢小刘同学提供的BGM，期望以后可以持续输出！ </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vlog 1  New Arrival</title>
      <link>https://www.marshalgao.com/posts/2020/08/vlog-1-new-arrival/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 14:44:52 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.marshalgao.com/posts/2020/08/vlog-1-new-arrival/</guid>
      <description>   疫情期间赴香港隔离，一路上新奇拍拍拍。要开始读书了，冲！ 特别感谢小刘同学提供的BGM，在这里夸赞一下她的歌品！ </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
