<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>This is Marshal</title>
    <link>https://www.marshalgao.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on This is Marshal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hku.hk&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;The University of Hong Kong&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 11:21:28 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.marshalgao.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>产品经理学习路线</title>
      <link>https://www.marshalgao.com/posts/2020/10/%E4%BA%A7%E5%93%81%E7%BB%8F%E7%90%86%E5%AD%A6%E4%B9%A0%E8%B7%AF%E7%BA%BF/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 11:21:28 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.marshalgao.com/posts/2020/10/%E4%BA%A7%E5%93%81%E7%BB%8F%E7%90%86%E5%AD%A6%E4%B9%A0%E8%B7%AF%E7%BA%BF/</guid>
      <description>方向选定及技能要求明确 （Oct）  了解B端产品类型，明确从事方向（Oct 19 - Oct 24）  重点了解广告及云服务产品经理   从JD入手，了解选定方向产品经理所需技能（Oct 25 - Oct 31)  相关技能的学习（Nov）  学习使用Axure，并对一些产品进行模仿（Nov 1 - Nov 8）   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ICOM6012 Transport Layer</title>
      <link>https://www.marshalgao.com/posts/2020/10/icom6012-transport-layer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2020 13:50:12 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.marshalgao.com/posts/2020/10/icom6012-transport-layer/</guid>
      <description>Transport-layer Services Transport Services and Protocols
 Provide logical communication (actually accomplished by network layer) between app processes on different hosts  logical communication means a pair of hosts is not connected physically, but it seems that they are connected by channel    Transport protocols run in end systems  send side: breaks app messages into segments (if needed), passes to network layer  using segment header, including port number, to communicate with the socket of receiver   receive side: reassembles segemnts into messages, uses segement header (or port number) to pass to application layer   More than one transport protocol available to apps  Majority: TCP and UDP  TCP: reliable, in-order delivery  congestion control flow control connection setup   UDP: unreliable, unordered delivery  no-frills extension of &amp;ldquo;best-effort&amp;rdquo; IP     Others: SCTP and DCCP  These protocols are very limited, so we just ignore them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://www.marshalgao.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 23:27:48 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.marshalgao.com/about/</guid>
      <description>This is Marshal. Currently, I am studying for a master&#39;s degree at the University of Hong Kong. My idea for blogging came from the Team Rocket, including Pseudoyu and Misty. In the blog, I would record my relevant courses of Electronic Commerce and Internet Computing of HKU, my interesting codes of LeetCode, knowledge and perspective of product manager, my personal thoughts and ideas about the life and friendship and vlogs about personal life in Hong Kong.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New</title>
      <link>https://www.marshalgao.com/posts/2020/10/new/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 19:52:36 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.marshalgao.com/posts/2020/10/new/</guid>
      <description>Bitcoin and Cryptocurrency Technologies Lecture 1 Introduction to Crypto and Cryptocurrencies Hash Function
 Takes any string as input Fixed-size output Efficiently computable  Security Properties
 Collision-free  Nobody can find x and y such as &amp;ldquo;x!=y and H(x)=H(y)&amp;quot;   Hiding  Given H(x), it&amp;rsquo;s infeasible to find x   Puzzle-friendly  For every possible output value y, if k is chosen from a distribution with high min-entropy, then it&amp;rsquo;s infeasible to find x such as H(k|x)=y    SHA-256 Hash Function</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[1] Two Sum</title>
      <link>https://www.marshalgao.com/posts/2020/10/1-two-sum/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 18:24:14 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.marshalgao.com/posts/2020/10/1-two-sum/</guid>
      <description>Question: Given an array of integers nums and an integer target, return indices of the two numbers such that they add up to target.
You may assume that each input would have exactly one solution, and you may not use the same element twice.
You can return the answer in any order.
Example 1: Input: nums = [2,7,11,15], target = 9 Output: [0,1] Output: Because nums[0] + nums[1] == 9, we return [0, 1].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vlog 2 Quarantine Diary</title>
      <link>https://www.marshalgao.com/posts/2020/09/vlog-2-quarantine-diary/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 14:12:35 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.marshalgao.com/posts/2020/09/vlog-2-quarantine-diary/</guid>
      <description>   疫情期间赴港上学隔离14天的生活即将结束，刚刚上完第一节课，视频传传好，我要冲了，努力学习！ 再次感谢小刘同学提供的BGM，期望以后可以持续输出！ </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vlog 1  New Arrival</title>
      <link>https://www.marshalgao.com/posts/2020/08/vlog-1-new-arrival/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 14:44:52 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.marshalgao.com/posts/2020/08/vlog-1-new-arrival/</guid>
      <description>   疫情期间赴香港隔离，一路上新奇拍拍拍。要开始读书了，冲！ 特别感谢小刘同学提供的BGM，在这里夸赞一下她的歌品！ </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
