<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ecom7122 on This is Marshal</title>
    <link>https://www.marshalgao.com/tags/ecom7122/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ecom7122 on This is Marshal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 10:01:44 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.marshalgao.com/tags/ecom7122/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>ECOM7122 Applied AI in Business</title>
      <link>https://www.marshalgao.com/ecom7122-applied-ai-in-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 10:01:44 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.marshalgao.com/ecom7122-applied-ai-in-business/</guid>
      <description>Intro to Applied AI Four pillars of applied AI
 every industry may use it contains  virtual assistance  apple siri, etc. chat robot   generating insights  machine learning   automation of manual processes  industrial robot machine or program replacement for routine work   unlocking unstructured data  used structured data in the past, but can unlock unstructured data, transferring the books on the shelf into database understand consumer conversations, e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ECOM7122 Introduction to Entrepreneurship and Lean Startup</title>
      <link>https://www.marshalgao.com/ecom7122-introduction-to-entrepreneurship-and-lean-startup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 09:41:47 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.marshalgao.com/ecom7122-introduction-to-entrepreneurship-and-lean-startup/</guid>
      <description>Lean Startup Approach Overview MVP
 definition  minimum viable product   schematic diagram  case - DropBox  its MVP is online video details     Comparison
 decade old formula  initiate business plan pitch your idea to investors assign the process to the right team launch roll your sales, marketing and profit making process hit or miss   lean startup  build minimum viable product measure understand customer feedback pivot or persevere launch sure to hit     The startup founder&amp;rsquo;s map</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
