<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>public key cryptography on This is Marshal</title>
    <link>https://www.marshalgao.com/tags/public-key-cryptography/</link>
    <description>Recent content in public key cryptography on This is Marshal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2020 09:43:16 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.marshalgao.com/tags/public-key-cryptography/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>ICOM6045 Public Key Cryptography</title>
      <link>https://www.marshalgao.com/icom6045-public-key-cryptography/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2020 09:43:16 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.marshalgao.com/icom6045-public-key-cryptography/</guid>
      <description>Public Key System Overview
 each party has 2 keys (no key distribution)  public key (open to the public) private key (secret to the owner)  mathematically, it is difficult to find the private key according to the public key security strength depends on key length   usage  encryption digital signature (unforgeable, no encryption -&amp;gt; message is public)  verfiy the origin of a message (not tampered) verify the identity of the sender (non-repudiation) reslove any authentication issues between the sender and the receiver   how to bind the private key and public key  using public key infrastructure  practical usage  encryption and signature can be used together combined with hash functions and symmetric key system  public key system depends on trap-door one-way function  examples  exponentiation: \(b = a^e\ mod\ p\) factorization: \(n = p\times q\)  RSA use this, except bitcoin (ECC) multiplication &amp;amp; factorization  e.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
