<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>entrepreneurship on This is Marshal</title>
    <link>https://www.marshalgao.com/tags/entrepreneurship/</link>
    <description>Recent content in entrepreneurship on This is Marshal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2021 11:57:06 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.marshalgao.com/tags/entrepreneurship/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>ECOM7122 Deep Learning</title>
      <link>https://www.marshalgao.com/ecom7122-deep-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2021 11:57:06 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.marshalgao.com/ecom7122-deep-learning/</guid>
      <description>Deep Learning Image &amp;amp; Voice Overview
 for applied AI four pillars  corresponding to unlocking unstructured data  AI &amp;ldquo;core&amp;rdquo; capabilities in language and vision natural language processing (NLP)     the &amp;ldquo;core&amp;rdquo; deep learning breakthroughs  vision - image recognition language - voice recognition    Fastest growing product in history
 result  conclusion  smart speaker increases the most quickly to 50% but smart speaker goes smoothly after 5 years, compared the continuous dramatical growth of smartphone and TV after reaching 50% (growth flatten)  may due to the loss of freshness may due to the loss of practicality      Cases</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ECOM7122 Blue Ocean Value Innovation</title>
      <link>https://www.marshalgao.com/ecom7122-blue-ocean-value-innovation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 18:06:17 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.marshalgao.com/ecom7122-blue-ocean-value-innovation/</guid>
      <description>Industry Life Cycle &amp;amp; Porter&amp;rsquo;s Five Forces Strategy toolbox
 firm-level analysis  target segments market size, etc.   industry-level analysis  competitive advantage analysis value chain analysis    Industry life cycle and five forces
 stages of the industry life cycle  Porter&amp;rsquo;s five forces analysis of industry profitability  influence  overall  average profitability  others  industries in the stages of Maturity and Decline will often seek government intervention or subsidies to help protect the declining industry often substitutes using innovation or new technology are the root cause of decline blue Ocean Strategy, sometimes called Value Innovation provides a new approach to managing mature or declining industries      Blue Ocean Strategy Red oceans vs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ECOM7122 Machine Learning, InsurTech and Ethical Considerations</title>
      <link>https://www.marshalgao.com/ecom7122-machine-learning-insurtech-and-ethical-considerations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 17:07:01 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.marshalgao.com/ecom7122-machine-learning-insurtech-and-ethical-considerations/</guid>
      <description>Machine Learning &amp;amp; Heart Attack Risk Overview
 traditional medical systems  treat illness when people are already sick   the reason of using machine learning  more accurate  20% - 30% better performance (means better prediction)   &amp;ldquo;unbiased&amp;rdquo;  statistical vs prejudicial bias   fast  automated decision making system but some decision making system may generate risks   cheap  predictive models work 24/7 can provide medical services all the time      Scorecard</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ECOM7122 Competitive Advantage and Profitability Analysis</title>
      <link>https://www.marshalgao.com/ecom7122-competitive-advantage-and-profitability-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 10:36:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.marshalgao.com/ecom7122-competitive-advantage-and-profitability-analysis/</guid>
      <description>Competitive Advantage Defined Strategy toolbox
 firm-level analysis  target segments market size mission statement, etc.   industry-level analysis  competitive adavantage analysis value chain analysis   tips  competitive advantage analysis requires &amp;ldquo;zooming out&amp;rdquo; to industry-level analysis, looking at the forest as well as the trees    Industry &amp;amp; market
 industry  many companies companies that make similar products or services   market  many buyers buyers of an industry&amp;rsquo;s products and services    Industry average profitability or &amp;ldquo;grades&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ECOM7122 Applied AI in Business</title>
      <link>https://www.marshalgao.com/ecom7122-applied-ai-in-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 10:01:44 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.marshalgao.com/ecom7122-applied-ai-in-business/</guid>
      <description>Intro to Applied AI Four pillars of applied AI
 every industry may use it contains  virtual assistance  apple siri, etc. chat robot   generating insights  machine learning   automation of manual processes  industrial robot machine or program replacement for routine work   unlocking unstructured data  used structured data in the past, but can unlock unstructured data, transferring the books on the shelf into database understand consumer conversations, e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ECOM7122 Introduction to Entrepreneurship and Lean Startup</title>
      <link>https://www.marshalgao.com/ecom7122-introduction-to-entrepreneurship-and-lean-startup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 09:41:47 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.marshalgao.com/ecom7122-introduction-to-entrepreneurship-and-lean-startup/</guid>
      <description>Lean Startup Approach Overview MVP
 definition  minimum viable product   schematic diagram  case - DropBox  its MVP is online video details     Comparison
 decade old formula  initiate business plan pitch your idea to investors assign the process to the right team launch roll your sales, marketing and profit making process hit or miss   lean startup  build minimum viable product measure understand customer feedback pivot or persevere launch sure to hit     The startup founder&amp;rsquo;s map</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
